## Aaron Anderson

## aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com

832-651-1700

### Objective

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience managing iOS mobile applications from front-end to backend, start to finish. An adaptable, goal-oriented, team player who is self sufficient and motivated to finding reliable solutions to new problems.

- Swift 4.0 / Java / Python / SQL / PostgreSQL / Django / Flask / Zendesk / JIRA / Taiga / RESTful APIs / MongoDB / Docker / Matplotlib / Scikit-learn / Gevent / Circus / Nginx
- SDKs (iOS and Android): Fabric / Stripe / Google Maps /
  Alamofire / TRON / SwiftyJSON / Facebook / Twitter / Firebase /
  Parse / Twilio / Charts / GSON / Picasso / Retrofit / EventBus

#### Experience

**Lead Mobile Engineer**; InteractiveTel LLC, Houston,TX — 2016-Present

Oversee iOS and Android creations, functionalities and interactions. Work with a team to push integrated features to production.

- Execute MVC patterns and developed practical modeling schemas.
- Created various API's, notifications and data models.
- Engineered app functionality to coincide with speech recognition.
- Tested data transmission through BLE connections.
- Created white noise filters for communication clarity.
- Applied Sql techniques and database modeling.
- Leveraged data persistence through Core Data, Caching and File management.
- Analyze data and make custom reports using scripts.
- Managed two admin. apps as well as two consumer apps.

## Aaron Anderson

## aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com

832-651-1700

 Created multiple Python backend servers and scripts using Pycharm

**Mobile App Developer**; Candorson LLC, Houston,TX — 2014-2016 Work with a team of developers to complete mobile applications from the initial stages to the finished product. Proficient in wireframes, Sketch and MVC techniques to efficiently complete work in a prompt manner. Problem solver and detailed oriented.

Projects consist of but not limited to:

Bubble Bazooka(iOS game)

Postablur(Social Media)

Koncrete(Shopping)

Mattress One (Interactive Training)

TForce Security(CMS)

Languages include:

Xcode (Swift)

PHP

Android Studio (Java)

SQL

**VMS QA/QC Systems Assistant**, Cenergy International; Houston,TX — 2014-2015

Supervised and assisted on managing the Inspections of Maintenance Program, HSE Program, Drug and Alcohol Program, Inspections and Assisted in managing quality assurance and quality control (QA/QC) to all customer units under the QA/QC Project and Systems Manager.

# Aaron Anderson <a href="mailto:aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com">aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com</a> 832-651-1700

- Maintain system efficiency, standards and data centers
- Perform daily systems monitoring and backup operations
- Test Systems and aid in implementations
- Research and apply data models
- Authorized payments and report delinquent accounts
- Create and remove user accounts
- Aid in creating codes and system queries
- Supervise Audits

**Junior Systems Administrator**, The Hosting Block Hosting; Houston, TX - 2015 - June 2016

Administrator for thehostingblock.com. Monitored the functioning of dedicated servers and answered technical inquiries. Maintain the upkeep and uptime of the site as well as manage backups of data and performance.

- Supervised server access and created SQL databases; including billing systems
- Troubleshoot system errors and connectivity issues.
- Maintain an uptime of 99.8% of system servers and security features
- Manage IP transfers and migrations
- Generate and assign SSL Certificates
- Run cron jobs, install apache mods and Mod-Security

# Aaron Anderson <a href="mailto:aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com">aaronanderson.anderson@gmail.com</a> 832-651-1700

• Configure C-panels, phpmyAdmin, MySQL databases, DNS Zone records, account functions and backup configurations.

### Education

Stephen F Austin State University, Nacogdoches, TX - BS in I/O Psychology 2014

### Leadership

Member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity Incorporated – Vice President

Member of Alpha Phi Omega Fraternity - Member

Neuroscience Lab Assistant - Undergrad

UX Team Lead- Postablur

Team Lead- Mattress One Mobile App Development

#### References

(Upon request)